Guide to the George Stade papers,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
George Stade Papers,
1973-2009.
Stade, George
5.25 linear ft. (4 record storage cartons, 1 document box)
Columbia University. Rare Book and Manuscript Library New York, NY. 10027
MS#1537
7831955
Author, and Columbia University Professor of English.
Biographical Note
Writer and professor of English and Comparative literature at Columbia University, George Stade, is an author and respected literary critic.
Stade received his PhD in English at Columbia University in 1965. after receiving his degree he remained at the University as an instructor, and remained at Columbia for over forty years, the duration of his academic career. Stade published both regularly in both academic and popular publications. He wrote four novels, Confessions of a Lady-Killer, Sex and Violence, A Love Story, Love is War, and Swimming Through the Flotsam in Which we Live and Have Our Being, as well as a collection essays, and numerous articles, reviews, and introductions for journals such as Partisan Review, Hudson Review, Paris Review, Harper's Magazine, Nation, New Republic, and The New York Times Book Review. He acted as the Consulting Editor Director of Barnes and Noble Classics and Editor-in-Chief of Scribner's British Writers Series and the fourteen-volume European Writers Series.
Scope and Content
The collection is primarily composed of manuscript drafts of Stade's four novels. Though Stade's fiction comprises the bulk of the material, the collection also includes a draft of Stade's doctoral dissertation and correspondence with colleagues and students.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged in 2 series
Series I: Manuscripts, circa 1980-2009
Series II: Correspondence, 1973-1997
Subjects
Stade, George.; Universities and colleges--United States--Fiction.; Manuscripts.; Galley proofs.
Access Restrictions
You will need to request this material at least two dusiness days in advance to use the collection in the Rare Book and Manuscript Library reading room.
This collection has no restrictions.
Acquisition
Columbia University English Department Gift 07/06/2010
- Series I: Manuscripts, circa 1980-2009
  - Confessions of a Lady-Killer (Box 4)
    - Early Notes and Outline (Box 4)
    - Manuscript, (7 Folders) (Box 4)
    - Proofs, (2 Folders) (Box 4)
  - Curriculum Vitae and Bibliography (Box 1)
  - Love is War Manuscript, (6 Folders) (Box 1)
  - Robert Graves on Poetry: 1916-1927-- Dissertation Draft (Box 1)
  - Sex and Violence, A Love Story, (6 Folders) (Box 1)
  - Sex and Violence, A Love Story, (11 Folders) (Box 2)
  - Swimming Through the Flotsam in Which We Live and Move and Have Our Being, (11 Folders) (Box 3)
- Series II: Correspondence, 1973-1997
  - Goodman, William, 1979-1980 (Box 5)
  - Graver, David (Box 5)
  - Gray, Francine1986 (Box 5)
  - Heise, Ursula, 1997 (Box 5)
  - Kennedy, Ray, 1984 (Box 5)
  - Kilfeather, Siobhan, 1991-1992 (Box 5)
  - Koch, Kenneth, 1980 (Box 5)
  - Kosiuski, Jerzy, 1973 (Box 5)
  - Lish, Gordon, 1983-1986 (Box 5)
  - Locatelli, Carla, 1983-1992 (Box 5)
  - Matthews, Harry, 1984 (Box 5)
  - Montgomery, John, 1977-1987 (Box 5)
  - Poirier, Richard, 1974-1981 (Box 5)
  - Rothman, David, 1985-1986 (Box 5)
  - Shaw, Peter, 1994 (Box 5)
  - Simkin, Diane, 1982-1983 (Box 5)
  - Solotaroff, Theodore, 1973 (Box 5)
  - Tomkins, Jane, 1984 (Box 5)
  - Trilling Award, 1978 (Box 5)
  - Turner, Peter, 1983-198 (Box 5)
  - Vendler, Helen (Box 5)
  - Viereck, Peter, 1974-1987 (Box 5)
  - Weinstein, Arnold (Box 5)
  - Williams, John A., 1974 (Box 5)
  - Wood, Michael, 1976-1990 (Box 5)